<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="cs">
    <title></title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>Nápojový lístek</title>
        <published>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Tomas Korcak &lt;korczis@gmail.com&gt;
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/jidelni-listek/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/jidelni-listek/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/jidelni-listek/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;jidelni-listek&quot;&gt;Jidelní lístek&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detail about točená piva goes here. You can include images, descriptions, or a beer list.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>Nápojový lístek</title>
        <published>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Tomas Korcak &lt;korczis@gmail.com&gt;
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/napojovy-listek/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/napojovy-listek/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/napojovy-listek/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;tocena-piva&quot;&gt;Točená piva&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detail about točená piva goes here. You can include images, descriptions, or a beer list.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>Piva Lahvová</title>
        <published>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Tomas Korcak &lt;korczis@gmail.com&gt;
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/piva-lahvova/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/piva-lahvova/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/piva-lahvova/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;lahvova-piva&quot;&gt;Lahvová piva&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detail about točená piva goes here. You can include images, descriptions, or a beer list.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>Piva Točená</title>
        <published>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Tomas Korcak &lt;korczis@gmail.com&gt;
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/piva-tocena/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/piva-tocena/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/piva-tocena/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;tocena-piva&quot;&gt;Točená piva&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detail about točená piva goes here. You can include images, descriptions, or a beer list.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>Terms</title>
        <published>2020-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Thomas Weitzel
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/terms/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/terms/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/terms/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These terms have been last updated on January 8, 2020&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All content on this web site is for informational purposes only.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the owner of this web site, I ...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make no representations as to the accuracy or completeness of any information on this site or by following any link.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will not be liable for any errors or omissions in this information, nor for the availability of this information.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will not be liable for any losses, injuries, or damages from the display or use of this information.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These terms are subject to change at any time and without notice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>About</title>
        <published>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Thomas Weitzel
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/about/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/about/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/about/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-am-i&quot;&gt;Who am I?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is &lt;strong&gt;Thomas Weitzel&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
When people have trouble pronouncing my last name, I suggest to try &lt;em&gt;White Cell&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.
If you want to call me by my nickname, that&#x27;s fine, too.
It is &lt;strong&gt;Thomy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, pronounced like &lt;em&gt;Tommy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work as an independent software developer since more than twenty years.
Industries I&#x27;ve worked in include Finance, Health Care, Automotive, Military, and Government.
Mostly I worked on internal projects, but also some software products.
My mother tongue is German.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-the-topic&quot;&gt;What&#x27;s the topic?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog covers my findings while exploring various aspects of programming in general, with a special focus on functional programming.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-motivation&quot;&gt;The motivation?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do people climb mountains?
British mountaineer George Mallory famously answered: &lt;em&gt;Because they&#x27;re there&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.
They want to reach the top faster, in a more efficient or elegant way, differently than anybody else, or even at all.
That&#x27;s how you approach problem-solving in programming.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-expect&quot;&gt;What to expect&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&#x27;m coming from an object-oriented background, expect all sorts of problems I&#x27;m stumbling into and then getting out of.
C, C++, and Java were my first professionally used programming languages.
Later I switched to Scala, and even later to Kotlin.
I had, and still have, a lot to learn, even more to unlearn, and I&#x27;m not nearly done yet.
If you&#x27;re having a similar background, maybe you can get something out of my mistakes and the occasional success.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-or-not-do-there-is-no-try-yoda&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do, or not do. There is no try&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. – Yoda&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision is not between doing something or not.
It&#x27;s that &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is something more than just any attempt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>Imprint</title>
        <published>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Thomas Weitzel
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/imprint/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/imprint/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/imprint/">&lt;!-- Add two spaces after each line to enforce line break --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Weitzel&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Theodor-Heuss-Str. 21&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;63225 Langen (Hesse)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Germany&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copying and redistribution of all my pages for private, non-commercial use is permitted provided this notice is attached.
See section &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pivniceutygra.cz&#x2F;pages&#x2F;imprint&#x2F;#copyright&quot;&gt;Copyright&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for more information.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;liability-for-content&quot;&gt;Liability for content&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a service provider I&#x27;m responsible according to Article 7(1) TMG (Germany) for my own contents on these pages according to the general laws.
According to Article 8 to 10 TMG (Germany) I am not obliged to monitor transmitted or stored third-party information or to investigate circumstances that indicate an illegal activity.
Obligations to remove or block the use of information under general law remain unaffected.
A liability in this regard is only possible from the date of knowledge of a specific infringement.
Upon notification of violations, I will remove such content immediately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;liability-for-links&quot;&gt;Liability for links&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My website contains links to external websites of third parties over whose contents I have no influence.
Therefore, I&#x27;m not liable for these external contents.
The provider or operator of these pages is always responsible for the contents of the linked pages.
At the time of linking I have checked the linked pages for possible legal violations.
Illegal content was not recognizable at the time of linking.
A permanent control of the content of the linked pages is not reasonable without concrete evidence of an infringement.
Upon notification of violations, I will remove such links immediately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;copyright&quot;&gt;Copyright&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content and works created by me on these pages are subject to copyright law.
Reproduction, adaptation, distribution, and any kind of exploitation outside the limits of copyright require my written consent.
Downloads and copies of these pages are for private, non-commercial use only.
As far as it wasn&#x27;t me who created the contents on these pages, I respect the copyright of third parties.
In particular, content of third parties is marked as such.
Still, should you be aware of a copyright infringement, please let me know.
Upon notification of violations, I will remove such content immediately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="cs">
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <published>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2019-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Thomas Weitzel
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/privacy/"/>
        <id>https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/privacy/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://www.pivniceutygra.cz/pages/privacy/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-protection&quot;&gt;Data protection&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of my website is possible without providing personal data.
If personal data can be entered (for example: name, address, or email addresses), this is on a voluntary basis.
These data will not be disclosed to third parties without your explicit consent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data transmission in the Internet (e.g.
in the communication by email) can have security gaps.
A complete protection of the data from access by third parties is not possible.
The use of contact data published in the imprint by third parties for sending me unsolicited advertising and information materials is hereby prohibited.
I reserve the right to take legal action in the event of unsolicited promotional information, such as spam emails.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hosting&quot;&gt;Hosting&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I host my website at netcup. The provider is netcup GmbH, Daimlerstr. 25, 76185 Karlsruhe, referred to as &quot;netcup&quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details on netcup&#x27;s privacy policy can be found on their homepage under &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.netcup.eu&#x2F;kontakt&#x2F;datenschutzerklaerung.php&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of netcup is based on Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.
I have a legitimate interest that my website is available to visitors as reliably as possible.
If consent was requested, data processing takes place exclusively based on Article 6(1)(a) GDPR.
Consent can be revoked at any time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-processing&quot;&gt;Data processing&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have signed a data processing contract with netcup.
This contract is required by privacy law and guarantees, that data of visitors of my website will be processed in compliance with the GDPR.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;responsible-controller&quot;&gt;Responsible controller&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The person responsible for data processing on this website is the person named in the [imprint]({{&amp;lt; relref &quot;imprint&quot; &amp;gt;}}).
The &quot;responsible controller&quot; means the natural or legal person who decides on the processing of data (for example: name, address, or email addresses).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;information-cancellation-deletion&quot;&gt;Information, cancellation, deletion&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any time you have the right to free information about your stored personal data, its origins, recipients, and the purpose of the data processing, as well as a right to correction or deletion of this data.
You can contact me at any time via the address given in the imprint for further questions on the subject of your personal data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;log-files-on-the-server&quot;&gt;Log files on the server&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web server stores information in its log files, some of which your browser transmits to me.
These are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the IP address of your computer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the time of the request&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the name of the requested page&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a status code (if the request was successful or not)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the referrer URL&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the browser type, browser version and other information sent by your browser&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data can not be used to identify a specific person.
I will not merge this data with other data sources.
I reserve the right to check this data retrospectively, if I become aware of illegal use of my website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ssl-encryption&quot;&gt;SSL encryption&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site uses SSL encryption for security reasons and to protect the transmission of sensitive content, such as the requests you send to me.
An encrypted connection can be recognized by the fact that the address in the address bar of the browser starts with &lt;code&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and a lock symbol nearby.
If SSL encryption is enabled, the data you submit to me can not be read by third parties.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cookies&quot;&gt;Cookies&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site uses functional cookies only on pages where math formulas are displayed with the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mathjax.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;MathJax&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; library.
These cookies are only used in the context of MathJax and the display of math formulas.
The readability of the website represents a legitimate interest within the meaning of Article 6(1)(f) GDPR.
I do not use any other cookies on this website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;embedded-content-from-other-websites&quot;&gt;Embedded content from other websites&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posts on this site may contain embedded content (e.g. videos, pictures, comments, etc.).
Embedded content from other websites behaves just as if the visitor had visited the other website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These websites may collect information about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking services, and record your interaction with this embedded content, if you have an account and are logged in to this other site.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-rights-do-you-have-to-your-data&quot;&gt;What rights do you have to your data?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may request that I export your personal information, including any data you have provided to me.
In addition, you may request the deletion of any personal information I have stored about you.
This does not include the data that I need to keep for administrative, legal, or security-related purposes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
